Athauda Arachchige Dayan Madushanka Dias

New York, NY 11109 | 929-288-6725 | dayandias20@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/dayan-dias | Portfolio

PROFILE

Master's student at Pace University specializing in software development with over 7 years of experience as a professional high caliber Naval Officer and over 2 years of experience in Java, DBMS, Multithreaded application and web technologies.

EDUCATION

Pace University, Seidenberg School of Computer Science and Information Systems

New York, NY

Master of Science (MS) in Computer Science

May 2021

GPA: 3.90

University of Kelaniya, Faculty of Science

Colombo, Sri Lanka

Bachelor of Naval Studies in Maritime Warfare

August 2015

GPA: 3.33 | **Honors:** Second Class (Upper Division) Honors

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Mobile Web Development (Responsive Web Development) | Parallel and Distributed Computing (Multithreaded and client-server applications) | Concepts and Structures in Internet Computing | Database Management Systems | Data Mining | Algorithms and Computer Theory | Fundamental Computer Science I and II | Computer Systems and Concepts

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: JAVA, C++, Python, JavaScript, React.js, Ionic Angular

Web Applications: HTML5, CSS, XML, JSON, AJAX Operating Systems: Windows OS, IOS, Android

Database: MySQL

Software: Adobe Creative Cloud (Adobe XD, Acrobat), Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel,

Access), WEKA, GIMP

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Predicting Liver Infection in Blood Test Dataset

April 2020 – June 2020

 Analyze a dataset of 'blood tests' in WEKA data mining tool using different data models to develop a prediction regarding liver infection diagnosis based on various sanguineous factors.

Responsive Web Development

Developed a responsive website using HTML5 and CSS to display various projects I have done individually and collaboratively.

Development of Web based application

• In the process of designing and developing a web-based application using React web framework to bring job seekers, employers and freelancers into a single platform, which will assist them in finding potential employers or employees (git-repo).

EXPERIENCE

Sri Lanka Navy Sri Lanka

Lieutenant, Staff Officer (Foreign Cooperation)

July 2015 – September 2017

- Established MySQL databases for 'Bilateral and multilateral engagements with foreign navies' and 'Galle Dialogue Maritime Symposium', both which had various data of over 72 navies, which minimized 30% of time and effort while maintaining data security and accuracy.
- Provided strategic consulting and political analysis for the Commander of the Navy in bilateral/multilateral engagements with other navies, which lead to acquire 4 ships and initiate bilateral engagements with 2 foreign navies.

Sub Lieutenant July 2010 – July 2015

- Maintained highest naval professionalism while serving onboard various ships and craft in different capacities.
- Initiated and conducted more than 100 trainings for officers and sailors on emergency procedures and seamanship, which increased individual performance of personal by 23%.

AWARDS

Sri Lanka Navy, 'Sword of Honor' for the best Midshipman of the intake of Naval Officers in 2010	November 2012
Sri Lanka Navy, Highest aggregator of the intake of Naval Officers in 2010	November 2012

ACTIVITIES

Club Name: Pace Computing Society, Member April 2020 – Present

SKILLS

Persuasion, Collaboration, Adaptability, Emotional Intelligence, Analytical Reasoning.